So let's talk about Bullgit by
an example, let's talk about my
clock, our clock, that is so fast.
It was banned from GitHub.
So I'm Haroen and I will
be representing Bullgit.
A bit about me.
I work at Algolia, but that
doesn't really matter right now.
But if you want to ask about
it, it's perfectly normal.
Bullgit is important.
But
What's really, what I do when
I want to look at the time.
First, I tried to look
at this emoji, right?
The clock, but it's wrong.
It's not 10 past 10.
So then I had to find a solution and
the solution is basically like this.
So I go to a browser and enter
bullg.it/fast-clock, and then it loads.
And so this is a time as you can
see, it's completely correct,
except the year and everything else.
And so why is that?
Let's take a look at this
link at the bottom there.
View the code on book on GitHub, right?
Yeah.
So, something happened let's look. Luckily
I still had the code on my computer, so I
push it to GitHub and I cloned it again.
That's fast clock archive.
This one still exists, but.
This number is pretty big.
It's 157 megabytes for
the site you saw earlier.
How is that?
Like, these are the files.
They don't look very special.
It's just a Jekyll page.
Let's just take a look at the index HTML.
Is something there very big?
No, no, it's not very big.
We're just going to, so if
you're unfamiliar with the Jekyll
Syntax, Do I have a pointer here?
Yeah.
So here are going to take a look
at the data and the configuration
variable called site.time.
We're going to have it as an XML
schema, and also a regular RFC-822
date, the normal one, the one you saw.
So let's take a look at config.yml
to see what this time thing really is.
It's a string.
So this is the date string, and it's
going to be pushed to the site, perfectly
normal, static, whatever, or mostly, I think?
Static, a clock, something's wrong there.
Let's take a look again at this
archive now that it's public.
[Oh, that's too much]
Yeah.
Uh, at this archive.
So we're seeing something here.
That's a bunch of commits.
So why are there so many commits?
I don't really know.
So normally when you make a commit, right,
we're using GitHub pages, so then gets
her, we'll take this, this Jekyll site and
make it into a website available at bullg.it/fast-clock
as normal.
Right.
But you can also have
something in between.
Uh, CI as we call it
continuous integration.
And this one will look like this.
This is our,
configuration file for Travis.
So just, just regular shell and we
have a secure environment variable.
We'll see.
So let's take a look at the rest, right?
The script.
So we're starting with some sed, I
don't know if, um, Some of you might
be old enough to know about it.
I was not.
Uh, but I, I, I, uh, figured it out.
This is the best way to do it.
So we're going to edit, this is direct
editor on the comment line, and we're
going to replace with a regex or find
the line that has commits, colon, and
then we're going to put the commits
and then the build number of Travis.
Right?
Okay.
Hey, there's a, there's one done,
but exactly the same for time also
happens with a, with their command
on unix that's called time.
And then it's going to put this, this
time variable right now on Travis,
into the config.yml that we're using.
Somehow we're not using it for
anything yet. after success.
Oh, yeah, these two should
have been, uh, switched.
Sorry.
Uh, so this year we're going to
take the time, get the data and just
format it as we, as a Jekyll expect
and put it also in config.yaml is
this an in place replace and then
git config global push.
We're going to have a username, right.
And an email.
It's a Felix email, um, because he was,
volunteering to get all the emails.
So, and then the next thing we're
going to commit, and we're going
to commit with a nice, friendly
commit message to tell the time.
And then now we're getting interesting.
We're pushing to the
GitHub repository again.
So, what did we have earlier?
Right?
You make a commit and
the site gets built.
We made the commit and Travis runs, right?
It's like this now.
So what happens once this
commit has been made by Travis?
Not by me.
It runs again on Travis because
every commit triggers the.
Triggers the CI and then a new
version of the site can be built.
And this way is basically the most
efficient way you can make a clock ever.
And that's why we call it fast clock.
So bullgit, what does bullgit really mean?
It really mean bullshit on GitHub.
That's what bullgit is.
Okay.
So bullgit is a community of
devs and non-devs as well.
Uh, and we're all over the world.
Uh, we're mostly in Europe because yeah,
that's how the internet kind of works.
So if you know people in, in, in other
parts of the world, please tell them
to come to bullgit because we want to
have everyone from the whole world.
Uh, you can find this map
also on our, on our website.
And recently we existed since, four years.
So in, uh, June and our founder
actually is in the room, uh, there.
And, um, so that's it.
So how do we, how did we start?
So there was a contest on
Codepen and Tim and a few others.
They made this, uh, this nice talk.io
logo because talk.io was a new.
chat platform and it was about
the codepen channel on talk.io.
And so it started with chatted
on, on talk.io then later we
also had some on Google Hangouts
because talk.io kind of stopped,
but now we're mostly on Gitter.
So this is basically
what the site looks like.
Nowadays is a bit an older
screenshot, but we share things.
Or we give them feedback
and things like that.
So you should join a
developer group for fun.
You should join a developer developer group
for finding solutions to your problems,
to talk about whatever you want.
It doesn't need to be about developing.
It can be about you're feeling bad
today, and it helps to have people to
talk to. You also learn lots of things.
The, the clock example earlier
was the first time I did CI.
And it was fun. To share what you made.
If you make something cool, you make
it at work and make it that fun that we
can just have this, this, this circle
of people that know each other and
interest in each other, and that can
make your influence circle even bigger.
And we also can meet up at
conferences, but this advice does
not only go for developer groups.
Those are just goes for making bullshit,
make whatever you want, have fun doing it.
And you learn loads.
Last year, we met up at a view source
in Berlin, and now we are with,
with quite a few of us here.
So feel free to join us, follow us on
Twitter, uh, and watch out our website.
Thank you for your attention.